Adam L. Santone, PhD

- Round Rock, TX
- 765-490-8450
- **▼** Portfolio
- **GitHub**

- ⋈ adam.santone@gmail.com
- in LinkedIn
- ☆ Scholar
- R^G ResearchGate

Profile

Technical AI/ML/Data Science learning experience architect & educational product designer with extensive experience in crafting high-quality learning experiences. Strengths include video design, international collaboration, technical translational communication, analytical thinking, forward-looking problem-solving, and practical technical quantitative analysis skills.

Professional Experience

Senior Technical Instructional Designer

Emeritus Institute of Management (Emeritus.org) ₽

2020/10 - 2023/05

- Designed & developed start-to-finish exceptional AI/ML/Data Science training & professional certifications for specific learner profiles in partnership with world-class faculty, executive partners, & other stakeholders
- Oversaw the design & studio recording of over 300 technical instructional videos
- Built and maintained successful relationships with highly technical subject-matter experts & external partners
- Designed & developed accessible content, curricula, assessments, custom graphics, visualizations, & interactive experiences in multiple formats for e-learning & video-based training
- Designed custom automation & efficiency tools
- Practiced excellent communication, writing, & editing skills for knowledge transfer & skill development explaining technical content to a wide variety of audiences

Data Science Learning Experience Designer

Massachusetts Institute of Technology | Open Learning ∂

- Developed & delivered data science instructional content for Uruguayan learners
- Designed, developed, & delivered 20+ data science lessons
- Presented synchronous online instructor-led content weekly to 50+ learners

Invention Education Program Coordinator

Massachusetts Institute of Technology | Lemelson-MIT €

- Created, delivered, & maintained 10+ invention-themed educational products
- Created custom productivity, research, & visualization tools using R and Python
- Led hands-on workshops through instructor-led training

Professional Development Coordinator & Technical Media Producer

Florida State University | Learning Systems Institute (LSI) €

- Owned the design & development of 350+ short-format STEAM documentary videos tied to state and national learning standards
- Led the development of 50+ mathematics- and science-related 3D models and accompanying curriculum
- Led statewide instructor-led teacher professional development
- Supervised teachers, scientists, and university faculty as workshop staff

2019/05 - 2019/11

2018/03 - 2019/04

2012/02 - 2017/07

Adam L. Santone, PhD 1/2

Skills

R & Python

data wrangling, analysis, modeling, visualization, interaction, file manipulation, task automation

Data Visualization

Open Broadcaster Software, DaVinci Resolve

Graphics

color theory, UI/UX, interaction design, visual design principles

Machine Learning principle component analysis, regression, NLP, cluster analysis, classification

Adobe Creative Suite, Photoshop, Premiere, Illustrator,

Team Management

Quantitative Analysis and Modeling

interpersonal development, communication strategies, project plan development, efficiency tools development exploratory data analysis, correlation, factor analysis

Learning Management Systems

Technical Learning Experience Tools

Canvas, modular learning experience design

Quarto, Markdown, Jupyter, H5P, Trinket, Articulate Storyline

Instructional Design

Transferable Skills



learning objective development, cognitive load management, backward design, pedagogy, andragogy, Articulate, simulations, eLearning, ADDIE, storytelling multimodal communication, time management, process & document organization, workflow development, team interaction, adaptability, initiative, technology literacy

Education

PhD, Technology (Human Spatial Cognition and Gaming)

Purdue University

MS, Technology (Virtual Reality and Education)

Purdue University

MS, Horticulture (Plant Molecular Biology)

Purdue University

BS, Biology (Plant Science)

Henderson State University

Certificates

- CS50P: Introduction to Programming with Python, CS50, Harvard University ∂
- Python for Managers, Columbia Business School Executive Education ℰ
- Professional Graduate Certificate in Data Science, Harvard Extension School (21FS4F4HAEEW) &

Awards

Merit Award

Florida State University | Learning Systems Institute (LSI) Awarded 2013, 2014, 2015, 2016

Pole Star of the Quarter

Emeritus Institute of Management

Awarded 2022 for the development, dissemination, and implementation of custom design process automation tools

Outreach

Learning Experience Developer (multiple)

2019

BioBuilder.org | MIT Open Learning pk12 Action Group | MIT Full STEAM Ahead

Program Fellow, Graduate STEM Fellows in K-12 Education

2007

National Science Foundation (NSF), Purdue University

Project Counselor, Spaceflight and Life Sciences Training Program

2004

NASA (Kennedy Space Center, FL)

Adam L. Santone, PhD 2/2